Guide to the Dick Thornburgh Papers, 1932- AIS.1998.30.15
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Under-Secretary-General of the United Nations, 1992-1993; XV.
  - Financial Restructuring and Peacekeeping, 4.
    - Financial Restructuring of UN Departments
      - Updates and "follow-ups" on the UN Conference on Trade and Development (UNCTAD), May-July, 1992 (Box 965, Folder 12)
      - Updates and "follow-ups" on the Economic and Social Commission for Asia and the Pacific (ESCAP), May-July, 1992 (Box 965, Folder 13)
      - General material on restructuring the regional commissions of the UN, May-July, 1992 (Box 965, Folder 14)
      - Internal memoranda and Thornburgh's notes regarding department restructuring, May-July, 1992 (Box 965, Folder 15)
      - Field Operations Division (FOD) and Peacekeeping operations and activities, May, 1992-January, 1993 (Box 965, Folder 16)
      - Reports and summaries for the work of the Economic and Social Council (ECOSOC), June-July, 1992 (Box 966, Folder 1)
      - Updates and "follow-ups" to UN Conference on Environment and Development (UNCED), June-July, 1992 (Box 966, Folder 2)
      - Updates and "follow-ups" to UN Drug Control Program (UNDCP), June-July, 1992 (Box 966, Folder 3)
      - Updates and "follow-ups" to Economic and Social Commission for Western Asia (ESCWA), June-August, 1992 (Box 966, Folder 4)
      - General materials on restructuring the UN, June-September, 1992 (Box 966, Folder 5)
      - Updates and "follow-ups" on Economic Commission for Europe (ECE), July, 1992 (Box 966, Folder 6)
      - Updates and "follow-ups" on Economic Commission for Latin America and the Caribbean (ECLAC), July-September, 1992 (Box 966, Folder 7)
      - Internal memoranda regarding next phases of restructuring, July-October, 1992 (Box 966, Folder 8)
      - "Reflections on the Role of the United Nations in the Economic and Social Sectors: Elements for Reform," by Gert Rosenthal, Executive Secretary for Economic Commission for Latin America and the Caribbean (ECLAC), August 12, 1992 (Box 966, Folder 9)
      - Ford Foundation: UN financing, background materials for meeting of UN Financing Advisory Group at the Ford Foundation, September, 1992 (Box 966, Folder 10)
      - Ford Foundation: UN Financing Advisory Group meeting, briefing materials and agenda, October 30, 1992 (Box 966, Folder 11)
      - Ford Foundation: budgets and financing materials, April-November, 1992 (Box 966, Folder 12-13)
      - Development restructuring and concept paper regarding UN economic and social programs, August-October, 1992 (Box 966, Folder 14)
      - "Next Steps Toward Reform and Restructuring in the UN," and "The Work of the UN in Economic, Social and Environmental Sectors", October, 1992 (Box 966, Folder 15)
      - Administrative Committee on Coordination reports on committee functions, October 12, 1992 (Box 966, Folder 16)
      - Concept paper regarding restructuring UN economic and social problems, October 21, 1992 (Box 966, Folder 17)
      - Statement by Susan Shearouse, U.S. Adviser, to the 47th General Assembly regarding personnel questions, November 5, 1992 (Box 966, Folder 18)
      - "La Fonction Publique Internationale," statement by the Secretary-General (SG) to the General Assembly, November 6, 1992 (Box 966, Folder 19)
      - "Note by the Secretary-General (SG) on questions raised by delegation and responses provided by the representative of the Secretary-General", December 4, 1992 (Box 966, Folder 20)
      - Advisory Committee for the Commission on Sustainable Development regarding three new UN Departments and their functions, December 13, 1992 (Box 966, Folder 21)
      - Secretary-General's (SG) Bulletin to staff regarding organization of the Secretariat: Department of Administration and Management, December 24, 1992 (Box 966, Folder 22)
      - Internal memoranda regarding reform of the economic and social sectors, December, 1992-February, 1993 (Box 967, Folder 1)
      - UN news releases: budget implications and economic concerns, October 5-December 22, 1992 (Box 967, Folder 2-4)
      - Development of three new UN Departments: Department of Policy Coordination and Sustainable Development, Department of Economic and Social Information and Policy Analysis, and Department of Development Support and Management Services, January, 1993 (Box 967, Folder 5)
      - Population and Population Statistics development support and management activities, January 25, 1993 (Box 967, Folder 6)
      - Transfer of Office of Project Services (OPS) to the Secretariat, January 25, 1993 (Box 967, Folder 7)
    - Financial Restructuring of UN with Consideration for UN Peacekeeping Efforts and Programs
      - Economic Commission for Africa (ECA), restructuring and peacekeeping, 1991-1992 (Box 967, Folder 8)
      - "The Looming Crisis in Health and the Need for International Support: Overview of the Reports on the Commonwealth of Independent States and the Baltic Countries," prepared by the WHO and the United Nations Children's Fund (UNICEF), February 17-March 2, 1992 (Box 967, Folder 9)
      - Task Force on the Secretary General's (SG) Summit Report on Security: "Report on Preventative Diplomacy," regarding peace-making and peacekeeping, February-April, 1992 (Box 967, Folder 10)
      - Task Force on the Secretary General's (SG) Summit Report on Security: internal memoranda and Thornburgh's notes, March-April, 1992 (Box 967, Folder 11)
      - Task Force on the Secretary General's (SG) Summit Report on Security: internal memoranda and drafts regarding creation of report, March-April, 1992 (Box 967, Folder 12)
      - Task Force on the Secretary General's (SG) Summit Report on Security: internal comments of first draft of report, May-June, 1992 (Box 967, Folder 13)
      - Task Force on the Secretary-General's (SG) Summit Report on Security: final report, "An Agenda for Peace: Preventative Diplomacy, Peace-making and Peacekeeping", June 17, 1992 (Box 967, Folder 14)
      - Vladimir Petrovsky, Under-Secretary-General (USG) for Political Affairs, "six month plan-of-action" for restructuring and peacekeeping, February-June, 1992 (Box 967, Folder 15)
      - United Nations Transitional Authority in Cambodia (UNTAC), financing and funding peacekeeping efforts, February-October, 1992 (Box 967, Folder 16)
      - Department of Economic and Social Development (DESD), "six month plan-of-action" for restructuring and peacekeeping, March-June, 1992 (Box 968, Folder 1)
      - Staffing and financing of peacekeeping Operations (PKO), March, 1992-January, 1993 (Box 968, Folder 2)
      - Department of Public Information, "six month plan-of-action" for restructuring and peacekeeping, April, 1992 (Box 968, Folder 3)
      - James O. C. Jonah, Under-Secretary-General (USG) for Political Affairs, "six month plan-of-action" for restructuring and peacekeeping, April-May, 1992 (Box 968, Folder 4)
      - Office of Legal Affairs (OLA), "six month plan-of-action" for restructuring and peacekeeping, April-June, 1992 (Box 968, Folder 5)
      - Jan Eliasson, Under-Secretary-General for Humanitarian Affairs, "six month plan-of-action" for restructuring and peacekeeping, April-June, 1992 (Box 968, Folder 6)
      - Comprehensive examination of the administrative operations of the Office of Conference Services (OCS), restructuring and peacekeeping efforts, June 24, 1992 (Box 968, Folder 7)
      - Notes, correspondence and reports on the Department of Administration and Management (DAM) and its role in world peace affairs, from McKinsey & Co. consultants, April-October, 1992 (Box 968, Folder 8)
      - "UN Progress Review," a report prepared by McKinsey & Co. consultants, August 27, 1992 (Box 968, Folder 9)
      - "Look Up to the 3rd Basement: Pilot Project of the Diplomatic Pouch Unit, Department of Administration and Management," a report prepared by McKinsey & Co. consultants, September 30, 1992 (Box 968, Folder 10)
      - "Achieving Superior Performance: Department of Administration and Management, final presentation," a report prepared by McKinsey & Co. consultants, October 16, 1992 (Box 968, Folder 11)
      - Outstanding contributions to regular budget and peacekeeping operations, by country, October, 1992-January, 1993 (Box 968, Folder 12)
      - "Field Mission Issues: Discussion meeting with Richard Thornburgh," a report prepared by McKinsey & Co. consultants, November 23, 1992 (Box 968, Folder 13)
      - Peacekeeping operations in former Yugoslavia, February-October, 1992 (Box 968, Folder 14-15)
      - Peacekeeping operations in Somalia, December, 1992-January, 1993 (Box 968, Folder 16)
  - Events and Schedules, 5.
    While at the United Nations Thornburgh was invited to many events and here the researcher will find an array of the UN related meetings, luncheons, symposia, dinners and events he attended. The time span these records cover is February 1992-February 1993. These files are arranged in alphabetical order, by event, and many have Thornburgh annotations.
    Here there also are schedules of Thornburgh's daily and weekly activities during his time at the UN. Some of these are working schedules, meaning that they contain handwritten notes of Thornburgh's events and activities during his year. The schedules also contain his acceptances for events, mostly dinners and luncheons, during his year at the UN.
    - ABC News interview with Allan Frank and Richard Greenberg, New York, February 8, 1993 (Box 969, Folder 1)
    - Abou-Zahr, Omar, Executive Secretary and President of Coordinating Committee for Independent Staff Unions and Associations (CCISUA), New York, October 15, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 2)
    - Administrative Committee on Coordination (ACC) Annual Meeting, New York, October 20-21, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 3)
    - Aita, Judy, USIA Press Service, Interview, New York, June 17, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 4)
    - American Bar Association, Standing Committee on World Order Under Law Meeting, New York, May 27, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 5)
    - American Legion 74th Annual Convention, Distinguished Service Award presented to Thornburgh, Chicago, IL, August 26, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 6)
    - Anestis, Robert and Matt, meeting, New York, July 27, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 7)
    - Bateman, Ray, President of Public Affairs Consultants, meeting with Max Otte to present KUP, Inc.'s services in Strategy and Organization for the Public Sector, Governmental Organizations and International Institutions, New York, September 3, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 8)
    - B'nai B'rith International, meeting with Dr. Harris Schoenberg, New York, June 25, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 9)
    - Borovoi, Konstantin, Luncheon honoring Borovoi hosted by Institute of East-West Dynamics, New York, August 31, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 10)
    - Bourn, Sir John, Comptroller and Auditor General of the United Kingdom, and Martin Sinclair, UK Director, Audit Operations and UN Board of Auditors, Meeting, New York, October 29, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 11)
    - Bush, President George, Tribute to George Bush Luncheon, Washington, DC, January 12, 1993 (Box 969, Folder 12)
    - Business Council for the UN, Global Forums for Business Leaders Luncheon, New York, September 9, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 13)
    - Canadian Broadcasting Corporation interview with Sue Simpson regarding documentary, "Waste and Mismanagement at the United Nations," New York, February 9, 1993 (Box 969, Folder 14)
    - Caswell, Janice, Editor of BCUN Briefing, Interview for Winter 1992 publication, New York, October 29, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 15)
    - Chase Manhattan Bank, Luncheon with Bob Douglas and Hugh Fierce, New York, June 22, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 16)
    - Chemical Bank Corporation, International Advisory Board Dinner, New York, November 30, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 17)
    - Committee on Contributions luncheon and reception, New York, June 25, 1992, June 29, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 18)
    - Commonwealth Club Luncheon with Under Secretary General Vladimir Petrovsky, New York, December 11, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 19)
    - Conway, Daniel, Director of United Nations Border Relief Operation (UNBRO), Meeting, New York, October 27, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 20)
    - Cotret, Robert de, Secretary of State of Canada and Minister Responsible for the Status of People with Disabilities, Meeting regarding Ministerial Conference in Montreal, New York, September 15, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 21)
    - Council of American Ambassadors Spring Meeting, New York (cancelled), April 27, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 22)
    - Curzon, David, meeting regarding Central Evaluation Unit, New York, September 14, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 23)
    - Dennis, Patricia Diaz, Assistant Secretary of State for Human Rights and Humanitarian Affairs, meeting, New York, September 15, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 24)
    - World Committee for the UN Decade of Disabled Persons, "Continuing the Momentum" Luncheon, New York, July 9, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 25)
    - DMG Associates Meeting regarding United Nations Development Programme (UNDP) Support Costs Study, New York, September 2, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 26)
    - Dowdeswell, Elizabeth, Executive Director of the United Nations Environment Programme (UNEP), Meeting, New York, February 10, 1993 (Box 969, Folder 27)
    - European Community (EC) Countries Luncheon honoring Secretary-General Dr. Boutros Boutros-Ghali, New York, June 17, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 28)
    - E-J Electric Installations Co., Breakfast with J. Robert Mann, Jr., New York, June 12, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 29)
    - Executive Secretaries of Regional Commissions, Meeting, New York, July 8, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 30)
    - External Audit Meeting with Osei Prempeh, Auditor-General of Ghana and Chairman of the United Nations Board of Auditors, regarding Work of the Board of Auditors, New York, June 22, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 31)
    - External Board of Audit Dinner in honor of Dr. Heinz Gunter Zavelberg, President of the Federal Court of Audit of Germany, New York, June 30, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 32)
    - Fall, Ibrahima, Assistant Secretary General for Human Rights, Meeting, New York, January 18, 1993 (Box 969, Folder 33)
    - Fiduciary Trust International Luncheon, New York, June 5, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 34)
    - Fifth Committee of the General Assembly, Speech, New York, October 13, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 35)
    - Foreign Policy Association Luncheon with Boutros Boutros-Ghali, Secretary General of the United Nations, New York, October 16, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 36)
    - Greindl, Major General Gunther, Chief Military Observer of the United Nations Iraq-Kuwait Observation Mission (UNIKOM), Meeting, New York, July 8, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 37)
    - Gillibert, Michel, French Minister for the Disabled, Phone call, New York, January 25, 1993 (Box 969, Folder 38)
    - Dag Hammarskjold Memorial Scholarship Fund of the United Nations Correspondents Association, Thirty-first Anniversary Luncheon, New York, September 15, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 39)
    - Hastings College of the Law, University of California, Attorneys General Forum, San Francisco, CA, September 19, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 40)
    - Hoegh, Hans, Secretary-General's Special Representative for the Promotion of the United Nations Decade of Disabled Persons, Meeting, New York, October 5, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 41)
    - Howse, Jennifer L., Ph.D., President of March of Dimes, Luncheon, New York, July 19, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 42)
    - International Meeting of Ministers Responsible for the Status of Persons with Disabilities, Montreal, Quebec, October 8-9, 1992 (Box 969, Folder 43)
    - Interviews of Candidates for Director of International Computer Center (ICC), New York, January 8, 1993 (Box 969, Folder 44)
    - Investments Committee Meeting, New York, September 28, 1992 (Box 970, Folder 1)
    - Jasper, Herbert N. and Collins Reynolds, Meeting, New York, February 18, 1993 (Box 970, Folder 2)
    - Jennings, Sir Robert, President of International Court of Justice, Meeting, New York, October 22, 1992 (Box 970, Folder 3)
    - Joint Inspection Unit (JIU) Chairman, Adib Daody and Erica-Irene A. Daes, Meeting, New York, October 19, 1992 (Box 970, Folder 4)
    - Kimble, Melinda, U.S. Deputy Assistant Secretary, Meeting, New York, August 27, 1992 (Box 970, Folder 5)
    - King, Nicholas, Director of Foreign Press Center (USIA), Meeting, New York, July 24, 1992 (Box 970, Folder 6)
    - Komarov, Governor, Murmansk Providence, Russian Federated Republic, Luncheon hosted by the Institute of East-West Dynamics and Trans-Ocean Express, Ltd., New York, June 30, 1992 (Box 970, Folder 7)
    - Lake Mohonk, Seminar on the Methodology for the Preparation of the Programme Budget, Introduction, New Paltz, April 22-28, 1992 (Box 970, Folder 8)
    - Lake Mohonk, Seminar on the Methodology for the Preparation of the Programme Budget, Relationships between Programmes and Budget, New Paltz, April 22-28, 1992 (Box 970, Folder 9)
    - Lake Mohonk, Seminar on the Methodology for the Preparation of the Programme Budget, Preparation of the Budget Estimates, New Paltz, NY, April 22-28, 1992 (Box 970, Folder 10)
    - Lake Mohonk, Seminar on the Methodology for the Preparation of the Programme Budget, Treatment of Extrabudgetary Resources, New Paltz, NY, April 22-28, 1992 (Box 970, Folder 11)
    - Lake Mohonk, Seminar on the Methodology for the Preparation of the Programme Budget, Presentation of the Proposed Programme Budget, New Paltz, NY, April 22-28, 1992 (Box 970, Folder 12)
    - Lake Mohonk, Seminar on the Methodology for the Preparation of the Programme Budget, Summary and Overview Tables and Annexes of the 1992-1993 Proposed Programme Budget, New Paltz, NY, April 22-28, 1992 (Box 970, Folder 13)
    - Lake Mohonk, Seminar on the Methodology for the Preparation of the Programme Budget, New Paltz, NY, April 22-28, 1992 (Box 970, Folder 14)
    - Management Advisory Service (MAS) Meeting, New York, January 25, 1993 (Box 970, Folder 15)
    - McKinsey and Company, Inc., Shareholders Committee Dinner, New York, December 10, 1992 (Box 970, Folder 16)
    - McLennan, Ambassador Judy, Commission on the Status of Woman, Meeting, New York, June 18, 1992 (Box 970, Folder 17)
    - Mercersburg Academy, Alumni Luncheon, Mercersburg, PA, October 17, 1992 (Box 970, Folder 18)
    - Misztal, Major General Roman, United Nations Disengagement Observer Force (UNDOF) Commander, Meeting, New York, July 23, 1992 (Box 970, Folder 19)
    - United Nations Committee of the New York State Bar Association Luncheon, New York, December 3, 1992 (Box 970, Folder 20)
    - NHK, Japan Broadcasting Corporation, Interview regarding documentary on United Nations' changing role since the end of the Cold War, New York, February 24, 1993 (Box 970, Folder 21)
    - O'Con-Solozano, Thelma, Director of UN Information Center, Meeting, New York, September 9, 1992 (Box 970, Folder 22)
    - OCS Staff Representatives, Meeting, New York, December 1, 1992 (Box 970, Folder 23)
    - Overseas Press Club of America, Scholarship Luncheon, New York, January 28, 1993 (Box 970, Folder 24)
    - Pennsylvania Bar Association Annual Meeting, Hershey, PA, May 7-8, 1992 (Box 970, Folder 25)
    - Pennsylvania Society, 94th Annual Dinner, New York, December 12, 1992 (Box 970, Folder 26)
    - Perkins, Ambassador Edward J., Representative of the United States of America to the United Nations, Luncheon in honor of United Nations/Host Country/Host City Relations, New York, July 22, 1992 (Box 970, Folder 27)
    - Perkins, Ambassador Edward J., Representative of the United States of America to the United Nations, Dinner in honor of the Honorable Richard L. Thornburgh and Mrs. Thornburgh, New York, October 5, 1992 (Box 970, Folder 28)
    - Global Philanthropy and United Nations Priorities--An Informal and Exploratory Conversation, Breakfast Meeting with C. W. (Bud) Leeds, III, New York, September 15, 1992 (Box 970, Folder 29)
    - Puchala, Professor Donald and Professor Roger Coate, University of South Carolina, Meeting, New York, September 10, 1992 (Box 970, Folder 30)
    - Ramachandran, Dr. Arcot, Under-Secretary-General and Executive Director of United Nations Centre for Human Settlement (Habitat), Meeting, New York, June 24, 1992 (Box 970, Folder 31)
    - Ridge, Congressman Tom, Meeting, New York, December 10, 1992 (Box 971, Folder 1)
    - Riza, Iqbal, Special Representative of the Secretary-General, Chief of Mission of United Nations Observer Mission in El Salvador (ONUSAL), Meeting, New York, June 30, 1992 (Box 971, Folder 2)
    - Sadik, Dr. Nafis, Executive Director of United Nations Population Fund (UNFPA), Meeting, New York, November 10, 1992 (Box 971, Folder 3)
    - Sanbar, Samir, Special Representative for the United Nations Observer Mission to Verify Referendum in Eritrea (UNOVER), Meeting, New York, February 4, 1993 (Box 971, Folder 4)
    - Sherwood, Charles and M. McCook Miller Jr., Meeting, New York, July 9, 1992 (Box 971, Folder 5)
    - Shparo, Dmitry, President of Moscow Adventure Club, Meeting, New York, August 28, 1992 (Box 971, Folder 6)
    - Sobchak, Anatoly, Mayor of St. Petersburg, Russia, Luncheon, New York, June 4, 1992 (Box 971, Folder 7)
    - Sokalski, Henryk, Director of Social Development Division and Coordinator for the International Year of the Family, 1994, Meeting, New York, July 24, 1992 (Box 971, Folder 8)
    - Staff-Management Coordination Committee (SMCC), Annual Meeting, New York, June 15-19, 1992 (Box 971, Folder 9)
    - Staff-Management Coordination Committee (SMCC), Meeting agenda and reports, New York, June 15-19, 1992 (Box 971, Folder 10)
    - United Nations Staff Day, New York, September 11, 1992 (Box 971, Folder 11)
    - Stafford, Douglas, Deputy High Commissioner for Refugees, Meeting, New York, January 5, 1993 (Box 971, Folder 12)
    - Stopford, Michael, Director of United Nations Information Center (UNIC), Meeting, Washington, DC, October 27, 1992 (Box 971, Folder 13)
    - Sysoev, Igor, Funeral Service, New York, July 22, 1992 (Box 971, Folder 14)
    - Thapa, Major General Krishna, Chief Staff of the United Nations Truce Supervision Organization (UNTSO), Meeting, New York, January 20, 1993 (Box 971, Folder 15)
    - Third World Permanent Representatives Luncheon hosted by Ambassador Jonathan Moore, New York, September 17, 1992 (Box 971, Folder 16)
    - Tremeaud, Francois, Deputy Director of International Labor Office (ILO), Meeting, New York, September 22, 1992 (Box 971, Folder 17)
    - Truman, John, CAO ESCWA, Meeting, New York, September 22, 1992 (Box 971, Folder 18)
    - UK Foreign Affairs Committee, Meeting, New York, November 10, 1992 (Box 971, Folder 19)
    - UK Members of Parliament, Meeting, New York, February 24, 1993 (Box 971, Folder 20)
    - United Nations Ambassadors Dinner, Business Council for the United Nations Medal Awarded to Thomas R. Pickering, United States Ambassador to India, New York, September 16, 1992 (Box 971, Folder 21)
    - UNA-USA Leadership Meeting, New York, July 13, 1992 (Box 971, Folder 22)
    - Walzer, Gerald, United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) Controller, Meeting, New York, September 3, 1992 (Box 971, Folder 23)
    - Washington, DC Visit by Boutros Boutros-Ghali, Secretary General of the United Nations, Washington, DC, May 11-13, 1992 (Box 971, Folder 24)
    - Wisconsin Public Radio Program, "Reforming the United Nations," New York, December 2, 1992 (Box 971, Folder 25)
    - World Affairs Council of Pittsburgh Luncheon, Pittsburgh PA, January 29, 1993 (Box 971, Folder 26)
    - World Bank Luncheon in honor of Wilfried Thalwitz, World Bank Vice President for Europe and Central Asia, New York, July 24, 1992 (Box 971, Folder 27)
    - Yale Center for International and Area Studies Symposium, "United Nations: Problems of Peacekeeping," New Haven, CT, October 31, 1992 (Box 971, Folder 28)
    - Daily Schedules, March, 1992-February, 1993 (Box 971, Folder 29-40)